const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following muscles shows a positive Trendelenburg sign when paralyzed?","answers":[{"option":"Gluteus medius","bool":true},{"option":"Gluteus maximus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor fascia lata","bool":false},{"option":"Quadratus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Piriformis","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"During mastectomy and axillary node removal, the surgeon observes a lateral thoracic vein encircling a group of axillary nodes. Which group of nodes are observed?","answers":[{"option":"Central","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Apical","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoral","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A tennis player presents with complaints of pain while at rest at night, especially when lying on the affected shoulder, and weakness while lifting or rotating the arm. The physician diagnoses it as an injury in the shoulder region and predicts the involvement of four muscles. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Frozen shoulder","bool":false},{"option":"Rotator cuff tear","bool":true},{"option":"Bursitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tendinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Acromioclavicular joint injury","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 26-year-old male is brought to the emergency department with complaints of numbness in the medial three toes of his left foot. He is diagnosed with tarsal tunnel syndrome. Which of the following nerves is most likely involved in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial peroneal","bool":false},{"option":"Tibial","bool":true},{"option":"Deep peroneal","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral","bool":false},{"option":"Common peroneal","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"During limb surgery, ligating the posterior tibial artery at its origin would result in absent blood flow in which artery?","answers":[{"option":"Descending genicular","bool":false},{"option":"Profunda femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior tibial","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsalis pedis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral plantar","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"An infantry army officer develops painful flat feet after several years of service including hundreds of miles of marches. The pain is more on the medial aspect of the sole. Which of the following structures is most likely strained in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Plantar calcaneonavicular (spring) ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Extensor retinaculum","bool":false},{"option":"Calcaneal (Achilles) tendon","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Plantar calcaneocuboid (long plantar) ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 50-year-old woman is referred to a general surgeon by her general physician due to a painless swelling on the inside of her upper thigh. During the examination, a herniation is found below and lateral to the pubic tubercle. Where is the herniation most likely to be?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral sheath","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral vein","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral canal","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial inguinal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal canal","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What muscle originates from the upper eight ribs, inserts into the medial border and inferior angle of the scapula, and is supplied by the long thoracic nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Pectoralis minor","bool":false},{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavius","bool":false},{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"The coracobrachialis muscle originates from the coracoid process of the scapula and attaches to the medial aspect of the shaft of the humerus. Which of the following movements of the arm is assisted by coracobrachialis?","answers":[{"option":"Supination","bool":false},{"option":"Extension","bool":false},{"option":"Abduction","bool":false},{"option":"Rotation","bool":false},{"option":"Flexion","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female housemaid comes to the outpatient department with right knee pain. It began abruptly a few weeks earlier and improved only minimally with NSAIDs. The patient spends hours on her knee while working. Examination reveals no visible erythema or abrasions, but palpation reveals intense localized pain. Although the patient's range of motion is normal, she experienced severe pain while climbing stairs. Which of the following bursae is most likely affected?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrocnemius","bool":false},{"option":"Suprapatellar","bool":false},{"option":"Prepatellar","bool":true},{"option":"Popliteal","bool":false},{"option":"Anserine","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A male patient came to the hospital complaining of difficulty while walking and experiencing pain in his right thigh. Upon examination, it was observed that he had a weakness in hip flexion and knee extension. However, extension, abduction, and adduction of the hip were all fine, and so was the knee flexion. Based on these symptoms, which muscle is most likely to be injured in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Pectineus","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus femoris","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A patient presented with pain and weakness in their right arm after a motor vehicle accident. Upon examination, his arm was adducted, medially rotated, extended, and pronated. Which of the following injuries may have resulted in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Lesion in distal median nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesion of long thoracic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesion of proximal ulnar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Traction of lower trunk (C8-T1 roots)","bool":false},{"option":"Traction of upper trunk (C5-C6 roots)","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"The superficial branch of the ulnar nerve and the ulnar artery lie in the fibro-osseous tunnel, the tunnel of Guyon. Compression of the ulnar nerve in the tunnel of Guyon will lead to a loss of sensation in which of the following areas?","answers":[{"option":"Palmar aspect of lateral four fingers","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal aspect of medial three and a half digits","bool":false},{"option":"Palmar surface of the little finger and medial half of the ring finger","bool":true},{"option":"Palmar surface of tips of four and a half digits","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal aspect of the little finger and the medial half of the ring finger","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 33-year-old pregnant female came to the outpatient department with complaints of tingling and numbness of the right hand with pain and needle sensations, especially in the thumb and index finger. On examination, the fingers of the right hand were also swollen. The consultant diagnosed her with carpal tunnel syndrome. Which of the following nerves is compressed in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Musculocutaneous nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A beggar on the roadside was suffering from wrist drop in his left hand. What is the site of injury?","answers":[{"option":"Carpal tunnel","bool":false},{"option":"Wrist joint","bool":false},{"option":"Radial groove of humerus","bool":true},{"option":"Guyon tunnel","bool":false},{"option":"Head of ulna","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Three compartments divide the leg: anterior, posterior, and lateral, separated by intermuscular septa and interosseous membranes. What is the nerve supply to the lateral compartment?","answers":[{"option":"Deep fibular","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior tibial","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial fibular","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior tibial","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Regarding the popliteal fossa, which of the following structures is most deeply placed in the popliteal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Common fibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Small saphenous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cutaneous nerve of thigh","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following muscles initiates the unlocking of the knee from a locked position?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrocnemius","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor magnus","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteus","bool":true},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":false},{"option":"Quadriceps femoris","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A football player injures his ankle while attempting to tackle the ball, which resulted in a forceful eversion of his foot during play. The doctor diagnosed him with a sprained deltoid ligament. Which bone does not attach to this ligament?","answers":[{"option":"Cuboid","bool":true},{"option":"Talus","bool":false},{"option":"Navicular","bool":false},{"option":"Medial malleolus","bool":false},{"option":"Calcaneum","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"When a knife injures the superficial peroneal nerve, which muscle will become paralyzed?","answers":[{"option":"Peroneus longus","bool":true},{"option":"Extensor digitorum longus","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor hallucis longus","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor digitorum brevis","bool":false},{"option":"Peroneus tertius","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 30-year-old man fell from the third floor and landed on his feet in the parking area of his apartment. Radiographs revealed a fracture of the sustentaculum tali. Which muscle passing immediately beneath it would be adversely affected?","answers":[{"option":"Peroneus longus","bool":false},{"option":"Tibialis posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Tibialis anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor hallucis longus","bool":true},{"option":"Peroneus tertius","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following muscles in the medial thigh can avoid injury if the main nerve of the compartment is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"Gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Pectineus","bool":true},{"option":"Adductor brevis","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"An athlete injured his long planter ligament while playing leading to pain around his medial longitudinal arch. Which bone forms the summit of the arch?","answers":[{"option":"Talus","bool":true},{"option":"Cuboid","bool":false},{"option":"Navicular","bool":false},{"option":"Medial cuneiform","bool":false},{"option":"Calcaneum","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"An orthopedic surgeon is performing arthroscopy of the knee joint of a 30-year-old basketball player. He notices a damaged ligament that is attached to the medial wall of the lateral femoral condyle and inserted into the intercondylar eminence of the tibia. Which of the following intracapsular ligaments is he observing?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cruciate ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Medial collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Patellar","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cruciate ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 50-year-old female presented to the neurological outpatient department with complaints of hand numbness, which was diagnosed as carpal tunnel syndrome. Which area of the hand is spared in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Palmar surface of thumb","bool":false},{"option":"Skin over thenar eminence","bool":true},{"option":"Palmar surface of middle finger","bool":false},{"option":"Palmar surface of index finger","bool":false},{"option":"Nail bed of index finger","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following carpometacarpal joints allow adequate adduction and abduction in addition to flexion and extension?","answers":[{"option":"Forth","bool":false},{"option":"Third","bool":false},{"option":"Second","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth","bool":false},{"option":"First","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following bones does not take part in the formation of the wrist joint?","answers":[{"option":"Ulna","bool":true},{"option":"Triquetral","bool":false},{"option":"Lunate","bool":false},{"option":"Radius","bool":false},{"option":"Scaphoid","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following muscles contract simultaneously to cause adduction at the wrist joint?","answers":[{"option":"Flexor carpi radialis and extensor carpi radialis","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris and flexor carpi radialis","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor carpi radialis and extensor carpi ulnaris","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris and extensor carpi ulnaris","bool":true},{"option":"Flexor carpi radialis and extensor carpi ulnaris","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which joint is the superior radio-ulnar joint?","answers":[{"option":"Ball and socket","bool":false},{"option":"Pivot","bool":true},{"option":"Plane","bool":false},{"option":"Saddle","bool":false},{"option":"Hinge","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following is an incorrect statement regarding biceps brachii?","answers":[{"option":"Chief supinator of radioulnar joint","bool":false},{"option":"Bicipital aponeurosis forms the roof of cubital fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon inserted to radial tuberosity","bool":false},{"option":"Innervated by the branch of the lateral cord of the brachial plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Short head has intracapsular origin","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Regarding the microscopic features of muscles, T tubules are extensions of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcolemma","bool":true},{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoplasm","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A student is examining a slide of bone under a light microscope. Which of the following bone cells will he find along the surface of the bone?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoclast","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoblast","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Osteon","bool":false},{"option":"Chrondrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"During a demonstration, the structure and growth of long bones were discussed. Long bones grow in length due to which of the following reasons?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial growth of cartilage tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Appositional deposition of bone growth","bool":false},{"option":"Endochondral deposition of bone tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Removal of calcified cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial growth of bone tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What is the most likely feature to be observed as a result of failure of apoptosis?","answers":[{"option":"All bones would form as the same structure","bool":false},{"option":"The digits would be connected by webbing, and would not be separated","bool":true},{"option":"The proximo-distal patterning would not occur normally","bool":false},{"option":"The bones and muscles would not form","bool":false},{"option":"The overlying epidermis would not form","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Somites develop from which of the following embryological derivates?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral plate mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Paraxial mesoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"The Z disc is made up of which of the following proteins?","answers":[{"option":"Nebulin","bool":false},{"option":"Myomesin","bool":false},{"option":"Actin","bool":true},{"option":"α-Actinin","bool":false},{"option":"C-protein","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What is the primary function of titin in skeletal muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Provides elasticity and recoil to muscle fibers after stretching","bool":false},{"option":"Stabilizes the myosin filaments","bool":true},{"option":"Acts as an ATPase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Anchors the actin filaments to the Z-lines","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitates the release of calcium ions from the sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What is the distance between one actin filament and the next actin filament on the same sarcomere?","answers":[{"option":"Z line","bool":true},{"option":"H zone","bool":false},{"option":"A band","bool":false},{"option":"M line","bool":false},{"option":"I band","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"In resting skeletal muscle, what is the optimum length of the sarcomere at which it can contract with maximum force of contraction?","answers":[{"option":"1.8 mm","bool":false},{"option":"2.2 µm","bool":true},{"option":"2.5 µm","bool":false},{"option":"1.65 µm","bool":false},{"option":"3.0 µm","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Large amounts of ATP are cleaved to form ADP during the contraction process, and the greater the amount of work performed by the muscle, the greater the amount of ATP that is cleaved. What is the name of this phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Fenn effect","bool":true},{"option":"Ratchet theory of contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Power stroke","bool":false},{"option":"Actin power-stroke theory","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-bridge theory","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 28-year-old woman has reported experiencing weakness in the muscles of her face and neck, which has resulted in double vision and difficulty swallowing. Over time, the weakness has also affected her upper and lower limbs. She notes that the muscle weakness becomes more prominent in the evening. The cause of this condition is believed to be antibodies against which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Presynaptic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Motor end plate","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"An experiment was conducted to distinguish between the contraction mechanisms of skeletal and smooth muscles. The contractile properties of isolated guinea pig intestine and skeletal muscles were studied following stimulation. The key difference between the two muscle types is that skeletal muscle contraction requires, but smooth muscle contraction does not require, which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Troponin","bool":true},{"option":"Myosin","bool":false},{"option":"Myosin light-chain kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Actin","bool":false},{"option":"Calmodulin","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 5-year-old girl suffering from severe Hurler syndrome presents with corneal clouding, mental retardation, dwarfing, and coarse facial features. Degradation of mucopolysaccharides dermatan sulfate and heparin sulfate are affected. Which enzyme is deficient in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Heparan sulfamidase","bool":false},{"option":"α-L-Iduronidase","bool":true},{"option":"β-Glucuronidase","bool":false},{"option":"N-Acetylglucosamine","bool":false},{"option":"Iduronate sulfate","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A newborn is brought with multiple fractures with no history of major trauma, kyphosis, and delayed wound healing. Pediatrician suspects disease involving the inability of collagen to form fibers properly leading to bowing or fracture of long bones. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteomalacia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Paget disease","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which enzyme is responsible for the strength, stability, and cross-linking of collagen fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Hydroxy collagenase","bool":false},{"option":"Prolyl oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Elastase","bool":false},{"option":"Lysyl oxidase","bool":true},{"option":"Hyaluronidase","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following is a primary storage form of vitamin D?","answers":[{"option":"Cholecalciferol","bool":false},{"option":"7-dehydrocholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"1,25-dihydroxycholecalciferol","bool":false},{"option":"25-hydroxycholecalciferol","bool":true},{"option":"Ergocalciferol","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following hormones is responsible for inhibiting the resorption of bones by osteoclasts, reducing mobilization of calcium and inorganic PO4 from bones into the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":true},{"option":"Parathyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following is the least likely feature of osteoporosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bone mass is 1-2.5 SD below the mean peak bone mass","bool":true},{"option":"Severe osteopenia that significantly increases the risk of fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Common due to senile changes","bool":false},{"option":"Common after menopause","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of non-traumatic fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Osteomyelitis denotes inflammation of bone and marrow, virtually always secondary to infections. What is the most common organism causing osteomyelitis in sickle cell anemia patients?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed bacterial infections","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":true},{"option":"Group B streptococci","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 28-year-old male flips over an all-terrain vehicle and lands on his leg. On physical examination, there is intense palpation over the right shin but no shortening of the limb. The overlying skin is intact. A radiograph shows a right tibial and fibular midshaft fracture into multiple bone fragments. Which of the following terms best describes these fractures?","answers":[{"option":"Compound","bool":false},{"option":"Incomplete","bool":false},{"option":"Pathological","bool":false},{"option":"Comminuted","bool":true},{"option":"Displaced","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 55-year-old male with a history of pain and loss of sensation in his lower extremities, repeated trauma, and deformed joints presented to the outpatient department. Biopsy from gummatous lesion shows fibrinoid necrosis characterized by edematous granulation tissue containing numerous plasma cells and necrotic bone. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Infection by salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli causing osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased tendency of fracture due to age","bool":false},{"option":"Infection by Treponema pallidum","bool":true},{"option":"Osteomalacia due to vitamin D deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Why is aspirin considered unique among non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Decreases fever","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents episodes of gouty arthritis with long term use","bool":false},{"option":"It selectively inhibits cyclooxygenase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Irreversibly inhibits its target enzyme","bool":true},{"option":"Increases the risk of colon cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs is analgesic and antipyretic but weak as an anti-inflammatory drug?","answers":[{"option":"Celecoxib","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":true},{"option":"Indomethacin","bool":false},{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false},{"option":"Probenecid","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"The chronic use of aspirin as an analgesic may result in which of the following adverse effects?","answers":[{"option":"Headache","bool":false},{"option":"Vertigo","bool":false},{"option":"Gout","bool":false},{"option":"Heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric ulcer","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following is the primary cause of death from acetaminophen overdose?","answers":[{"option":"Liver failure","bool":true},{"option":"Status epilepticus","bool":false},{"option":"A-V conduction disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Acute nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Status asthmaticus","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Aspirin effect on blood clotting involves which of the following mechanisms?","answers":[{"option":"Activating antithrombin III and inhibiting thrombin","bool":false},{"option":"Blocking platelet receptor for ADP","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting hepatic vitamin K dependent clotting factor synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulate fibrinogenic synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Preventing platelet aggregation by inhibiting thromboxane A2 synthesis","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Erikson's theory proposes that each stage of psychosocial development is marked by a conflict or crisis that an individual must resolve. When a stage is not managed well, it can lead to a negative outcome, such as malignancy or maladaptation of behavior. Conversely, if the stage is managed too well, it can result in an overly positive disposition, such as a person who trusts too much. What is the term used to refer to this negative disposition?","answers":[{"option":"Conflict","bool":false},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Virtue","bool":false},{"option":"Ego dystonic","bool":true},{"option":"Crisis","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"One DALY represents the loss of one year of full health. It is mathematically represented by which one of the following equations?","answers":[{"option":"DALY = L + YLL (life expectancy at age of death + years of life lost)","bool":false},{"option":"DALY = DW + YLD (disability weight + years lived with disability)","bool":false},{"option":"DALY = DW + YLL (disability weight + years of life lost)","bool":false},{"option":"DALY = YLL + YLD (years of life lost + years lived with disability)","bool":true},{"option":"DALY = YLD + L (years lived with disability+ life expectancy at the age of death)","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What is the term used to describe the physiological ability of women to give birth to children?","answers":[{"option":"Fertility","bool":true},{"option":"Fecundity","bool":false},{"option":"General fertility rate","bool":false},{"option":"Total fertility rate","bool":false},{"option":"Reproductive life span","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What is the minimum number of X-ray views required to confidently rule out a scaphoid fracture in most cases?","answers":[{"option":"Single view is enough","bool":false},{"option":"Two standard X-ray views","bool":false},{"option":"Four X-rays views of scaphoid series","bool":true},{"option":"Five X-rays views of scaphoid series","bool":false},{"option":"Three X-ray views","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male patient presented to the emergency department with complaints of pain in his right knee after a fall. Although the x-ray was normal, the ER physician suspects a possible ligament injury. What would be the most appropriate next diagnostic test to confirm the condition?","answers":[{"option":"MRI of the right knee","bool":true},{"option":"CT scan of the right knee","bool":false},{"option":"Contrast enhanced CT scan of the right knee","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray of the right knee with additional views","bool":false},{"option":"None of the above","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"A 40-year-old woman came to the emergency department with a sign of foot drop. Which of the following nerves could have been damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Deep peroneal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial peroneal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits both cyclooxygenase 1 and 2?","answers":[{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":true},{"option":"Celecoxib","bool":false},{"option":"Misoprostol","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What happens when the apical ridge is removed?","answers":[{"option":"Regeneration of the entire limb bud from underlying mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Degeneration of the limb bud","bool":false},{"option":"Regeneration of new apical ridge from adjacent epidermal tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Continued development in the progress zone, once the apical ridge has induced progress zone formation","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of structures proximal to the apical ridge, but no formation of new distal structures","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following factors primarily determines the strength of a muscle contraction?","answers":[{"option":"The length of muscle at rest","bool":false},{"option":"The type of muscle fibers","bool":false},{"option":"The presence of acetylcholine receptors","bool":false},{"option":"The number of muscle fibers recruited","bool":true},{"option":"The thickness of sarcolemma","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"What is the term used to describe a system that records vital events such as births and deaths in a specific area?","answers":[{"option":"Vital registration","bool":true},{"option":"Population census","bool":false},{"option":"Demographic sample survey","bool":false},{"option":"Surveillance","bool":false},{"option":"Service statistics","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"During a motorbike accident, a 15-year-old boy lost sensory innervation from the medial side of the leg and foot. Which of the following statements is incorrect regarding the nerve involved?","answers":[{"option":"Branch of femoral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Content of adductor canal","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Accompany femoral vessels","bool":false},{"option":"No motor function","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"The force of a tetanic contraction is greater than that of a twitch contraction due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Longer duration of acetylcholine receptor at the neuromuscular junction","bool":false},{"option":"Increased calcium release","bool":true},{"option":"Increased release of acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid action potentials along T-tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased potassium in extracellular fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"In a scenario where there is insufficient ATP available during muscle fiber contraction, what is the immediate consequence?","answers":[{"option":"The muscle fiber remains contracted indefinitely","bool":false},{"option":"Troponin binds to myosin","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium ions are released from sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-bridges cannot detach, leading to prolong contraction","bool":true},{"option":"The muscle fiber relaxes immediately","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs are considered a directly acting muscle relaxant?","answers":[{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorzoxazone","bool":false},{"option":"Tizanidine","bool":false},{"option":"Succinylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Dantrolene","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2023","question":"ADHD is a condition that affects the development of the brain and has a lifelong impact. Research suggests that females with ADHD are more likely to go undiagnosed and untreated during childhood because their symptoms are often less noticeable and internalized compared to males. Which of the following is not a symptom found in females?","answers":[{"option":"Forgetfulness","bool":false},{"option":"Feeling shy","bool":false},{"option":"Distractibility","bool":false},{"option":"Daydreaming","bool":false},{"option":"Disruptiveness","bool":true}]}]
export default arr